[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
We've discussed a little bit of this loan application domain and
لقد ناقشنا القليل حول هذا المجال المتعلق بتقديم طلبات القروض،
showed you a little example of the decision tree.
وعرضنا مثالًا صغيرًا حول شجرة القرار.
Let's dive in and explore the decision tree a little bit further.
لذا، دعونا نتعمق أكثر ونكتشف شجرة القرار بشكل أبعد قليلًا.
So, I start for my loan application and I could go down one branch or
لذا، سأبدأ عند طلب الحصول على القرض هذا، ويمكنني النزول خلال فرع واحد
one path of this decision tree and say If this application somebody would
أو مسار واحد من شجرة القرار تلك، والقول إنه إذا كان هذا الطلب الذي قد يرغب شخص ما في ملئه
file credit that's fair and is a short-term loan,
وكان التصنيف الائتماني له جيد، وكان سداد القرض على مدى قصير،
let's say three year loan, then this is considered a risky application.
لنفترض أنه قرض لثلاث سنوات، فحينها يعتبر هذا الطلب يشكل مخاطرة.
If I take another path of the decision tree, let's say,
وإذا أخذت مسارًا مختلفًا من شجرة القرار، لنفترض،
I'll look at somebody whose credit is poor but the income is high but
أنني نظرت إلى طلب شخص ما حيث كان التصنيف الائتماني سيئ ولكن الدخل كان مرتفعًا،
it's a short term loan again, I might consider it a risky application.
وكان قرضًا على مدى طويل، فقد أعتبره طلبًا يشكل مخاطرة.
In general I'm going to be given an imput xi.
بشكل عام، سيكون لدي الإدخال Xi.
In this case it has assignments to each one of those input features that say
وفي هذه الحالة فسيكون لديه تخصيصات لكل واحدة من سمات الإدخال هذه، لنفترض أن
credit poor, income high, and term five years longer term loan.
تصنيف الائتمان سيء والدخل مرتفع وفترة السداد هي خمس سنوات، لذا فهو قرض طويل المدى.
And then I traverse the path down the tree to make a prediction which in this case
ثم أجتاز هذا المسار أسفل الشجرة، لإجراء التنبؤ، والذي في هذه الحالة
y hat i would be safe.
ستكون Yi^ هي قرض آمن.
So this is the model predicts to be a safe loan to make.
لذا، فهذا هو النموذج الذي يتوقع أن يشكل قرضًا آمنًا.
So just in generally, the task that we're looking at is given some input, xi, I'm
وبشكل عام، فإن العملية التي ننظر إليها تعطينا إدخالًا ما وهو Xi،
going to traverse the decision tree down the particular branches of that input,
وسأقوم بتخطي شجرة القرار هذه وصولًا إلى فروع القرارات لهذا الإدخال،
which in the example that we just did was a traversal that looks like this.
والتي في هذا المثال هي عبارة هذا المسار الذي يشبه بهذا الشكل.
And then I'm going to make a prediction y-hat i.
ثم سأقوم بإجراء التنبؤ Yi^.
Which might be that this loan is safe and so our goal is to learn that tree
والذي يمكن أن يؤدي إلى كون هذا القرض آمنًا، لذا فإن هدفنا هو التعرف على تلك الشجرة
T(x) that let's us make predictions about our data.
(T(x، وذلك ما يجعلنا نجري التنبؤات حول البيانات لدينا.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]